YAN BONNEL

JAVA AND ANDROID DEVELOPER

ybonnel@gmail.com https://github.com/ybonnel

Twiter: @ybonnel

Profile

Developer with 7 years experience on Java and more recently (about 2 years) on native Android development.

Skills

Java

I work with java for 7 years, I like very much community around Java, go to JUG, Devoxx, ...

Android

I develop on Android for 2 years on personnal projects.

HTML₅

I'm interested in new HTML technologies (like JQuery, Angular.js, JQuery Mobile, Twitter bootstrap).

Continuous delivery

I like to automate everything and have a real continuous delivery.

Technical

Java	Hibernate	HTML5	Jenkins
JEE	Play framework	CSS	Sonar
Spring	Android	Javascript/JQuery	Maven

Experience

Sopra Group Software Architect

02/2008 - now

Transversal technical leader on 4 Java applications, team of 30 people (from 05/2012 to now)

Applications in charge of network activation for a french mobile operator.

New application management contract with reversibility.

Work in team with Indian people.

- Continuous delivery: define build and install processes with Jenkins for all applications.
- Technical expert: support for all developers.
- · Help to resolve issues on multiple environments.
- Realisation of a Web portal for developers (Play framework).

Technologies:

- o Java
- o Ant
- Jboss
- Oracle
- Unix
- o Jenkins
- o Play Framework
- SVN

Technical leader on 2 Java applications, team of 100 to 200 people (02/2008 - 04-2012)

Redisign project of the core system for a french mobile operator.

This project covers from order to billing through a catalog for the offers' referential.

- $\circ~$ Bench of Cameleon Software (used for the catalog offers) 5 months
 - Use of Load Runner.

- Development of a webservice layer to abstract Cameleon (Jboss WS).
- Writing functionnal specifications for the catalog offers 6 months.
- Technical leader on the catalog offers, 5 to 10 developers 1 year
 - Webservices (JbossWS),
 - Hibernate,
 - Continuous integration (Maven, Hudson, Sonar).
- Technical leader on a taking order system, 10 to 30 developers more than 2 years
 - Webservices (CXF),
 - Spring core, JPA, Hibernate,
 - Continuous integration (Maven, Jenkins, Sonar),
 - Installation and integration of Gerrit (software to help in code revue),
 - Realisation of a Web portal for developers (Play Framework).

Technologies:

- o Java,
- Spring core,
- o Jboss,
- · Hibernate, JPA,
- Webservices (JbossWS and CXF),
- o Oracle,
- o Unix,
- o Maven,
- Jenkins,
- o Play Framework,
- o SVN,
- Git (used for Web portal).

Sopra Group

Junior Software Architect

11/2007 - 01/2008

Create an UI to manage documents (team of 5 people)

Application in charge of document management for all exploitation documents.

Functions

- $\circ~$ Participation in the pre-study for realisation.
- · Creation of the base code for the development.

Technologies:

- Java/JEE,
- o Struts,
- Hibernate,
- o SVN.

Sopra Group Developer

07/2006 - 10/2007

Participation in every steps of an Application Management Contract (team of 4 to 10 people)

Applications used for a mobile operator to know the list of network antennas which would be used by users.

Functions

- $\circ~$ C++ developments under Unix for an activation system.
- $\circ~$ JEE developments for an administration interface.
- Java developments under Windows for a forecasting system radio coverage.
- Participation in specifications and testing for these applications.

Technologies:

- o C++,
- o Unix/Shell,

- o Java/JEE,
- o Struts,
- o PVCS Version Manager,
- VBScript.

Sopra Group

02/2006 - 06/2006

Developer

Final-year internship

Participation in developing an activation system for a french mobile operator.

- C++ developments under Unix (HP UX),
- Unix Scripting (KSH).

Off-work projects

"Transports Rennes" and "Transports Bordeaux" github.com/ybonnel/TransportsRennes

08/2010 - now

Android applications for public transportation of Rennes and Bordeaux. Use of Open-Data for these two cities.

Some statistics:

- o Transports Rennes' downloads: more than 19 000,
- Transports Rennes' comments: more than 500 ratings with 4.642/5 average,
- o Transports Bordeaux' downloads: more than 18 000,
- Transports Bordeaux' comments: more than 250 ratings with 4.627/5 average,
- Source code: more than 30 000 LOC (Project on ohloh).

CsvEngine

05/2011 - now

github.com/ybonnel/CsvEngine

Small java framework based on annotations used to parse and write CSV files.

Transports Rouen

07/2012 - now

github.com/ybonnel/TransportsRouen http://transports-rouen.appspot.com

Small mobile web app for public bikes in Rouen. Used to test JQuery Mobile technology.

BreizhCamp github.com/breizhjug

2011 - now

Participation in all developments for web applications used by BreizhCamp. BreizhCamp is a two-day conference organized by Rennes' JUG.

Education

University of La Rochelle (France)

2000 - 2006

 ${\it Master in computer sciences (specialty: pattern \, recognition \, and \, image \, processing).}$

Yan Bonnel — ybonnel@gmail.com